Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Peter Gilow Papers, 1960-1978 RL.00696
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Clients Series, 1962-1978
  - 1962 July- 1969, Dec.: Bundespresseamt (Box 7)
  - 1962, Dec.- 1963, Aug.: Bank of Nova Scotia (Box 7)
  - 1963, Jan.-Dec.: A-Z, 17 folders (Box 7)
  - 1964, Jan.-Dec.: B-Ford, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - 1964, Jan.-Dec.: G-Z, 10 folders (Box 8)
  - 1966, Jan.-Dec.: A-Z, 6 folders (Box 8)
  - 1967, Jan.-1968, Dec.: A-So, 16 folders (Box 8)
  - 1967, Jan.-1968, Dec.: Sprengel-Z, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - 1969, Jan.-1970, Dec.: Ford-Z, 18 folders (Box 9)
  - 1970, June -1977 Sept: Unilever (central media buying), 2 folders (Box 9)
  - 1971, Jan.-1972, Dec.: Ford-Pepsi, 6 folders (Box 9)
  - 1971, Jan.-1972, Dec.: R-Z, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - 1973, Jan.-1975, Jan.: A-Z, 10 folders (Box 10)
  - 1975, Jan.-Dec.: Milupa (Box 10)
  - 1976, Jan.-Dec.: K-Z, 9 folders (Box 10)
  - 1977, Jan.-1978 May: A-Ko, 6 folders (Box 10)
  - 1977, Jan.-1978 May: Kraft-Z, 5 folders (Box 11)
- New Business Series, 1961-1976
  Comprised of correspondence, reports, minutes, market analysis drafts, notes, telexes, printed material, clippings and presentation material including photographs, scripts and screenplays for TV commercials. Arranged chronologically, the reports and minutes are filed at the beginning of the series, followed by correspondence with potential clients that is arranged chronologically and then alphabetically by client's name.
  - 1961 Jan.-1963 Dec.: Protokolle/minutes, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - 1964 Jan.-1968, Nov., 1969, Jan.-1970, June: Reports, minutes of the New Business-Committee, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - 1961 Oct.-1963 Dec.: A-Z, 6 folders (Box 11)
  - 1962 Jan.-1964 Dec.: A-G, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - 1964 Jan.-1966 Dec.: L-Z, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - 1966 Jan.-1967 Dec.: Correspondence with JWT New York (Box 11)
  - 1967 Jan.-1968 Dec.: A-Z, 7 folders (Box 11)
  - A-B, 1967 Oct.-1971 March: A-Z, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - 1971 April-1972 Dec.: A-Z, 6 folders (Box 12)
  - 1973 Jan.-1974 Dec.: A-Z, 7 folders (Box 12)
  - 1976 Jan.-Dec. A-Z, 6 folders (Box 12)
- Organizations Series, 1961-1978
  Consists of correspondence, statutes, minutes and protocols, brochures and bulletins, clients lists and circulars of the GWA, and notes and clippings. In the European Advertising Agencies Association (EAAA) files is a directory for its members that provides information about the member agencies' history, structure, affiliations, clients, turnover, and staff. Arranged alphabetically by organization, then chronologically.
  - Aktion Gemeinsinn (German Advertising Council): (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1961-1963, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1966, 1969-1970, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Aktion Gemeinsinn (German Advertising Council): (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 13)
    - General, 1964 (Box 13)
    - Minutes/Sitzungen und Protokolle, 1961-1963, 1965-1966, 1969-1970, 1973-1974, 5 folders (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967-1969 and undated (Box 13)
  - American Advertising Agencies Association, 1965, April-1966, March (Box 13)
  - Arc-Agency, 1977, Jan.-1978, Feb. (Box 13)
  - Basisresearch, 1977, Jan.-1978, Feb. (Box 13)
  - European Advertising Agencies Association:
    - Brochures and bulletins, 1960, Aug.-1962, Dec. (Box 13)
    - 1963, Jan.-1965, May (Box 13)
    - Directory A-Z, 1964, July-1966, May, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Directory and Membership Lists, 1964, July-1966, May (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1961, March-1966, May (Box 13)
    - Memoranda, 1964, March-1966, May (Box 13)
  - Gesellschaft Werbeagenturen (GWA):
    - Board, Aktennotizen, 1962-1963, 1968, Nov.-1969, Dec., 6 folders (Box 13)
    - Board, European Advertising Agencies Association, 1968, Oct.-1969, Aug. (Box 13)
    - Board, Verschiedene Vorgänge, 1964, Jan.-1970 Dec., 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Gesellschaft Werbeagenturen (GWA): (Box 14)
    - Board, Verschiedene Vorgänge, 1969, Jan.-1971, Feb., 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Board Meetings, 1962-1963, 1968-1969, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Correspondence, Board, 1962-1963, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Board, A-Z, 1968, Nov.-1969, Dec., 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Correspondence, general, 1962, Jan.-Dec. (Box 14)
    - Fördergemeinschaft, 1962-1963, 1966, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - GIW (Institut für Wirtschaftlichkeit in der Werbung), 1969 (Box 14)
    - Infopress, 1965 (Box 14)
    - Meetings, 1962-1963, 1966, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Members, Aktennotizen, 1962-1963, 1965-1969, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Members, Chefbriefe, 1969, Jan.-1971, Feb., 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Members, Client Lists, 1962-1963, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Members, Commercial Log, 1963, Jan.-Dec. (Box 14)
    - Members, Rundschreiben / Circulars, 1962, Jan.-May, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Gesellschaft Werbeagenturen (GWA): (Box 15)
    - Members, Rundschreiben / Circulars, 1962, June-1963, Dec., 1965, Jan.-1969, Dec., 12 folders (Box 15)
    - Personnel Profiles, 1963, Jan.-Dec. (Box 15)
    - Public Relations, 1963, Jan.-Dec. (Box 15)
    - Werbefachschule Frankfurt, 1963, Jan.-Dec. (Box 15)
    - Satzungen/statutes, 1961-1966 (Box 15)
  - JWT Public Relations GmbH, Proservice, 1977, Jan.-1978, April (Box 15)
- Meetings Series, 1960-1978 (bulk 1962-1970)
  Consists of minutes, correspondence, schedules, memoranda, research papers, bulletins, brochures, indexes of resolutions, recommendations, transcripts of speeches and presentations, financial reports, policy plans, notes and clippings. Arranged alphabetically by title of the meeting, then chronologically.
  - Board of Directors Meeting: (Box 15)
    - New York, 1976, Feb. and April, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - New York, Aug. 1976and Washington Oct. 1976 (Box 15)
    - New York, 1977, April, June, Aug., Oct., 3 folders (Box 15)
    - London, 1977, Dec. and New York, 1978, Feb. and April (Box 15)
  - Conference of Directors, 1975-1977, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Confidential and miscellaneous memoranda (Box 15)
  - European Managers Meeting:
    - 1962, Feb.: London (Box 15)
    - 1962, June: Frankfurt (Box 15)
    - 1962, Oct.: Milan (Box 15)
    - 1963, Jan.: Amsterdam (Box 15)
    - 1963, June: Frankfurt (Box 15)
    - 1963, Oct.: Brussels (Box 15)
    - 1964, Feb.: London (Box 15)
    - 1964, Dec.: Frankfurt; 1965, Feb.: Vienna (Box 15)
    - 1965, July: Antwerp (Box 15)
    - 1965, Nov.: Milan (Box 15)
    - 1966. June: Amsterdam (Box 15)
    - 1967, March: Brussels; 1967, July: Frankfurt (Box 15)
    - 1967, Sept.; London (Box 16)
    - 1968, March: Paris (Box 16)
    - 1968, Oct.: London (Box 16)
    - 1969, March: London (Box 16)
    - 1969, Oct: Madrid (Box 16)
    - 1969, Nov.: Miami (Box 16)
    - 1974, Oct.: London (Box 16)
    - 1976; Jan.: Amsterdam; 1976, March: Rome (Box 16)
    - 1976, May: Versailles (Box 16)
    - 1976, July: Zurich (Box 16)
    - 1976, Nov.: New York; 1976, Dec.: London (Box 16)
    - 1977, Feb.: London; 1977, April: Frankfurt (Box 16)
    - 1977, June: Stockholm; 1977, July: Palma de Mallorca (Box 16)
    - 1977, Sept.: Brussels (Box 16)
    - 1977, Dec.: London; 1978, Feb.: Athens (Box 16)
  - European Planning Committee: (Box 16)
    - 1973, Jan.-Dec. (Box 16)
    - 1973, Sept.: Milan; 1974, March: Frankfurt (Box 16)
    - 1974, Jan.: London; 1974, March: Frankfurt (Box 16)
    - 1974, May Amsterdam; 1974, Sept.: London (Box 16)
  - International Management Group: New York, 1973, July, Sept., Dec.; 1974, Jan., May, Aug., 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Management Committee, 1975, Jan.-1976, Dec. (Box 16)
  - New Business, 1975, Jan.-1978, Mar., 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Operating Committee, 1975, Jan.-1978, May, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Prokuristen Meetings, 1960, Dec.-1963, Dec., 3 folders (Box 16)
- Memoranda Series, 1961-1970
  Contains interoffice memoranda and several issues of Frankfurt's internal newsletter JWT Frankfurt Report. Arranged chronologically except Frankfurt's newsletter is filed at the end.
  - Haus-Mitteilungen: (Box 17)
    - 1961, Dec.-1963, Dec.: Frankfurt, 9 folders (Box 17)
    - 1966, Jan.-Dec.: By Peter Gilow, Frankfurt (Box 17)
    - 1966, Jan.-Dec.: Frankfurt (Box 17)
    - 1967, Jan.-Dec.: By Peter Gilow, Frankfurt (Box 17)
    - 1967, Jan.-Dec.: Frankfurt, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - 1967, Jan.-1968, Aug.: Frankfurt, Infratest (Box 17)
    - 1969, Jan.-Dec.: Frankfurt, general (Box 17)
    - 1969, Jan.-Dec.: Frankfurt, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - 1969, Sept.-1970, March: By Peter Gilow, Frankfurt (Box 17)
  - JWT-Frankfurt-Report, 1966, Feb.-Aug., 1969 March - 1970 May, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - J.Walter Thompson London, Round the Square, 1966 Jan.-Dec. (transferred to the JWT Newsletter Collection) (Box 17)
  - J.Walter Thompson New York, News, 1966-1967 (transferred to the JWT Newsletter Collection) (Box 17)
  - J.Walter Thompson Vienna, Report; J.Walter Thompson Amsterdam, 1966 Jan.-Dec. (transferred to the JWT Newsletter Collection) (Box 17)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1957-1978
  Comprised of notes, drafts, typescripts and printed material by Peter Gilow and other authors. The papers not written by Peter Gilow can be found at the beginning of the series, arranged alphabetically, then chronologically. Peter Gilow's writings and speeches follow in chronological order.
  - Not by Peter Gilow: (Box 17)
    - A-O, 1964-1966 (Box 17)
    - P-R, 1965-1966 (Box 17)
    - S, (Dan Seymour), 1962-1969 (Box 17)
    - S, (Norman H. Strouse), 1965 (Box 17)
    - S, (Thomas Sutton), 1957-1969 (Box 17)
  - Peter Gilow's writings and speeches: 1965-1970, 5 folders (Box 17)
  - Peter Gilow's writings and speeches: 1971-1978, 9 folders (Box 18)
- Annual Management Assessment and Objectives Series, 1966-1978
  Consists of reports, graphs, charts, statistics, and notes. Arranged alphabetically according to the name of the office then chronologically.
  - Frankfurt Office, 1966-1971, 1973-1978, 8 folders (Box 18)
  - London Office, 1972-1974 (Box 18)
  - Stockholm Office, 1973-1977, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Vienna Office, 1970-1971, 1972-1978, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Zurich Office, 1969-1970, 1972-1978, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - German-Speaking Area (Austria, Germany, Switzerland), 1977-1978 (Box 18)
- Manager's Monthly Assessment Series, 1971-1978
  Consists of reports, graphs, charts, statistics, and notes. Arranged alphabetically according to the name of the office, then chronologically. At the end of the series there is a European digest of these monthly assessments for the years 1976-1977.
  - Frankfurt Office, 1971-1974, 5 folders (Box 18)
  - Frankfurt Office, 1976-1978, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Stockholm Office, 1974-1978, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Vienna Office, 1973-1974, 1976-1978, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Zurich Office, 1973-1974, 1976-1978, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - European Managers Monthly Assessment, 1976-1977, 3 folders (Box 19)
- Account Poll Series, 1976 May
  Beginning with the summary of the final results, this series supplies the account poll's questionnaires, the staff's responses, their transcriptions, and several stages of their analysis.
  - J.Walter Thompson Internal Evaluation of Ad-Campaigns: (Box 19)
    - Summary, 1976, May (Box 19)
    - Transcript of the questionnaires' evaluation, 1976, May (Box 19)
    - Results, 1976, May (Box 19)
    - Preliminary results, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Transcript, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Opinions on non-J.Walter Thompson campaigns (Box 19)
    - Response originals, 1976, May (Box 19)
    - Unit A, 1976, May (Box 19)
    - Unit B, 1976, May (Box 19)
    - Unit C, 1976, May (Box 19)
    - Unit D, 1976, May (Box 20)
    - Other Clients, 1976, May (Box 20)
- International Visitors and Other Events Series, 1963-1976 (bulk 1975-1976)
  Consists of correspondence, telexes, memoranda, guest lists, schedules, notes, and clippings. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1963, Jan.-Dec. (Box 20)
  - 1969, Jan.-1970, April (Box 20)
  - 1975, Jan.-Dec., 3 folders (Box 20)
  - 1976, Jan.-Dec. (Box 20)